TANDID ALAM

tandid.alam@gmail.com

347-567-3824

Linkedin

Github

Portfolio

SKILLS React, Redux, Javascript, jQuery, CSS, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Webpack, Git, HTML5, Heroku, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Socket.io, Phaser.js

PROJECTS

The Hooded Hero (Phaser.js, Javascript, Socket.io, Node.js, Express, Webpack, HTML5, CSS)

Live Site | Github

A 2D platformer game where users can choose to go through a story mode with several stages or play with friends online to see who can come out on top.

- Implemented Phaser is and RexUI configurations for a seamless gaming experience through fast rendering and scene generation.
- Utilized Tiled application in order to create the blueprint for level design and specify the interactivity between player and objects.
- Applied game logic and physics by tracking the current play state and updating events based on collision, raycasting, and more.
- Incorporated Socket.io to communicate multiplayer based events with the server, allowing real-time gameplay with other players.

Buzzer (Javascript, JQuery, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Socket.io, Webpack, HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS)

<u>Live Site</u> | <u>Github</u>

A full stack single-page Twitter clone where users can create unique profiles, create and interact with posts, and chat with other users.

- Administered the use of WebSockets to allow individual users to chat with one another in real time or receive live notifications.
- Leveraged MongoDB's flexible document schema to make swift database updates throughout the development process.
- Imposed stylistic elements from bootstrap to build a cohesive styling structure synonymous to that of Twitter's web application.
- Implemented News API for compiling a list of the top three news articles at the current hour and directing users to those pages.

Poptoons Shop (React, Redux, Javascript, Stripe, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express.js Webpack, HTML5)

<u>Live Site</u> | <u>Github</u>

A full stack single-page E-commerce application where users can go through the full cycle of purchasing products while admins can manage the database of products.

- Devised a system for users to experience the typical flow of shopping from login, adding items to cart, payment, and checkout.
- Employed sessionStorage to allow guest users to merge their current cart with a newly created cart upon user creation or login.
- Built a Sequelize database to generate schemas and authorize clear relationships that users and admins have with their products.
- Integrated Material UI framework to provide high quality front-end graphics and stylized components for a clean user interface.

EXPERIENCE

Deloitte & Touche LLC, Audit Assistant New York, NY

2020-2021

- Assisted in the testing of KKR's Principal Activities Group consisting of 300+ private equity investments worth over \$500 billion.
- Collaborated with client and managers to determine discrepancies and materiality within internal controls and financial reporting.
- Spearheaded side projects to improve audit quality and workflow efficiency using excel computations and macro programming.

Aulder Capital, Acquisitions Analyst Intern New York, NY

2017-2018

- Reviewed 100+ potential deals through Offering Memorandums and capturing key property information into Pipeline Report.
- Conducted rent and sales comparisons using REIS and Yardi Matrix in order to evaluate the positioning of a given property.
- Spearheaded multiple projects which included economic analysis, comparative market analysis, and city screening analysis.

Maybank, Accounting/Finance Intern New York, NY

2017

- Prepared daily bank reconciliations in order to eliminate discrepancies within balance sheets of Nostro and Vostro accounts.
- Assisted manager in budgeting by evaluating monthly overhead expenses and organizing data into graphs for forecasting.
- Produced several regulatory and monthly reports using general ledger or chart of accounts and conducted audits for accuracy.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Academy New York, NY

2020

Immersive full stack software development bootcamp with an 8% acceptance rate, which entailed 1000+ hours of coding.

CUNY Bernard M. Baruch College New York, NY

2015-2020

- Bachelor of Business Administration, GPA: 3.6/4.00
- Major: Accounting Minor(s): Communications and Psychology

INTERESTS

ESports, Basketball, Bodybuilding, Cognitive Neuroscience, Piano, Day Trading, Biking, Snowboarding